Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950] PN6110 .P3
Lilly Library
- Parodies, [ca. 1850-1950]
  - Kipling, Rudyard, 1865-1936., 9 envelopes (Box 4, Item 29)
    - The Female of the Species. "When the Himalayan peasant meets the hebear in the pride" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 3)
    - Fuzzy-Wuzzy. "We've fought with many men acrost the seas" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 3)
    - The Gipsy Trail. (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 4)
    - Gunga Din. "You may talk o' gin an' beer" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 4)
    - If. "If you can keep your head when all about you" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 4)
    - The Men that Fought at Minded. "The men that fought at Minden, they was rookies in their time--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 4)
    - Mother O' Mine. "If I were hanged on the highest hill" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Islanders. "No doubt but ye are the People--your throne is above the King's." (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Ladies. "I've taken my fun where I've found it;" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Last Chantey. "Thus said the Lord in the Vault above the Cherubim" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Law of the Jungle. "Now this is the Law of the Jungle--as old and as true as the sky;" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Legend of Evil. "This is the sorrowful story" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Liner She's a Lady. "The Liner she's a lady, an' she never looks nor 'eeds--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - The Long Trail. "There's a whisper down the field" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 5)
    - Mandalay. "By the old Moulmein Pagoda, lookin' east-ward to the sea" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 6)
    - Oonts! "Wot makes the soldier's 'eart to penk, wot makes 'im to perspire?" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 6)
    - Laocoon. "Under the shadow of Death," Our Lady of the Snows. (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 6)
    - Recessional. "God of our fathers, know of old--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 6)
    - The Rhyme of Three Sealers (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - The Sea and the Hills. ""Who hath desired the Sea?--the sight of salt water unbounded--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - Sestina of the Tramp Royal. "Speakin' in general, I 'ave tried 'em all--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - Soldier An' Sailor too. "As I was spittin' into the Ditch aboard o' the Crocodile" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - The Song of the Banjo. "You couldn't pack a Broadwood half a mile--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - The Song of the Cities. "Where the sober-colored cultivator smiles" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - The Story of Ung. "Once, on a glittering ice-field, ages and ages ago" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - A Tale of Two Cities. "Where the sober-colored cultivator smiles" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - Tomlinson. "Now Tomlinson gave up the ghost in his house in Berkeley Square" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - Tommy. "I went into a public-'ouse to get a pint o' beer" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 7)
    - Ulster. ""The dark eleventh hour" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - The Vampire. "A fool there was and he made his prayer" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - "When 'Omer struck 'is bloomin' lyre" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - White Horses. "Trust ye the curdled hollows--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - The White Man's Burden. "Take up the White Man's burden--" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - The Widow at Winsor. (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - The Young Queen. "Her hand was still on her sword-hilt, the spur was still on her heel" (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 8)
    - Parodies in the style of Kipling, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 29, Envelope 9)
  - Knox, William, 1732-1810., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 30)
    - Oh Why Should the Spirit of Mortal be Proud?. "Oh, why should the spirit of mortal be proud?" (Box 4, Item 30)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 31)
    - Idealists. "Brother Tree: Why do you reach and reach?" (Box 4, Item 31)
  - La Conte, Marie R., 18--?, 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 32)
    - Somebody's Darling. "Into a ward of the whitewashed walls" (Box 4, Item 32)
  - Lamb, Charles, 1775-1854., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 33)
    - Angel Help. "This rare tablet doth include" (Box 4, Item 33)
    - The Older Familiar Faces. "I have had playmates, I have had companions" (Box 4, Item 33)
  - Lampson, Frederick Locker., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 34)
    - From the Cradle. "They tell me I was born a long" (Box 4, Item 34)
    - Tempora Mutantur. "Yes, here, once more a traveler" (Box 4, Item 34)
    - A Terrible Infant. "I recollect a nurse called Ann" (Box 4, Item 34)
    - Parody in the style of Lampson, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 34)
  - Landon, Letitia Elizabeth, 1802-1838., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 35)
    - The Violet. "Violets! deep-blue violets!" (Box 4, Item 35)
    - Parody in the style of Landon, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 35)
  - Landor, Walter Savage, 1775-1864., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 36)
    - "Twenty years hence my eyes may grow" (Box 4, Item 36)
  - Lang, Andrew, 1844-1912., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 37)
    - Homer. "Homer, thy song men liken to the sea" (Box 4, Item 37)
    - The Odyssey. "As one that for a weary space has lain" (Box 4, Item 37)
    - Parodies in the style of Lang, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 37)
  - Lanier, Sidney, 1842-1881., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 38)
    - Parodies in the style of Lanier, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 38)
  - Lawrence, David Herbert, 1885-1930., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 39)
    - Parody in the style of Lawrence, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 39)
  - Lear, Edward, 1812-1888., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 40)
    - The Ahkond of Swat. "Who, or why, or which or what" (Box 4, Item 40)
    - Lines to a Young Lady. "How pleasant to know Mr. Lear!" (Box 4, Item 40)
    - The Youghy-Bonghy-Bo. "On the coast of Cormandel" (Box 4, Item 40)
  - The Leather Bottel. "Twas God above that made all things.", 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 41)
  - Lever, Charles James, 1806-1872., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 42)
    - "The Pope he leads a happy life" (Box 4, Item 42)
    - The Widow Malone. "Did ye hear of the Widow Malone" (Box 4, Item 42)
  - Leland, Charles Godfrey, 1824-1903., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 43)
    - Hans Breitmann's Barty. "Hans Breitmann gife a barty;" (Box 4, Item 43)
    - The Water-Fay. "The night comes stealing o'er me" (Box 4, Item 43)
  - Leigh, Henry Sambrooke, 1837-1883., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 44)
    - The Twins. "In form and feature, face and limb" (Box 4, Item 44)
  - Lehmann, Rudolf Chamer, 1856-1929., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 45)
    - The Rad-Doll. "The Rag-doll here and the Rag-doll there! Take care of the Rag-doll, do!" (Box 4, Item 45)
  - LeGallienne, Richard, 1866-19--, 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 46)
    - Parody in the style of LeGallienne, original poem unidentified. (Box 4, Item 46)
  - Lewis, Matthew Gregory, 1775-1818., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 47)
    - Alonzo the Brave and Fair Imogene. "A warrior so bold, and a virgin so bright" (Box 4, Item 47)
    - The Fisherman. "The water rushed, the water swelled" (Box 4, Item 47)
    - On the Banks of Allan-Water. "On the banks of Allan-water" (Box 4, Item 47)
    - The Erl King. "Who is it that rides through the forest so fast" (Box 4, Item 47)
    - Parodies in the style of Lewis, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 47)
  - Lindsay, Nicholas Vachel, 1879-1931., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 48)
    - Parodies in the style of Lindsay, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 48)
  - Lines by a Lover. "Would you then know my Celia's charms?", 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 49)
    - "Would you then know my Celia's charms?" (Box 4, Item 49)
  - Little Ah Sid. "Little Ah Sid", 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 50)
  - Lockhart, John Gibson, 1794-1854., 1 envelope (Box 4, Item 51)
    - The Bridal of Andalla. "Rise up, rise up, Xarifa, lay the golden cushion down;" (Box 4, Item 51)
    - The Lamentation for Celin. "At the gate of old Granada, when all its bolts are barr'd" (Box 4, Item 51)
    - Parodies in the style of Lockhart, original poems unidentified. (Box 4, Item 51)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wordsworth, 1807-1882., 9 envelopes (Box 4, Item 52)
    - The Arrow and the Song. "I shot an arrow into the air" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 1)
    - The Arsenal at Springfield. "This is the Arsenal. From floor to ceiling" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 1)
    - Beware! "I know a maiden fair to see" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 1)
    - The Bridge. "I stood on the bridge at midnight" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - The Building of the Ship. "Build me straight, O worthy Master!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - The Celestial Pilot. "And now, behold! as at the approach of morning" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - Children. "Come to me, O ye children!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - Curfew. "Solemnly, mournfully" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - "The day is done, and the darkness" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - Daybreak. "A wind came up out of the sea" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 2)
    - Excelsior. "The shades of night were falling fast" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 3)
    - Evangeline. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 4)
    - Excelsior, cont. "The shades of night were falling fast" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 4)
    - Flowers. "Spake full well, in language quaint and olden" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - The Hemlock Tree. "O hemlock tree! O hemlock tree! how faithful are thy branches!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - Hymn to the Night. "I heard the trailing garments of the Night" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - The Ladder of St. Augustine. "Saint Augustine! well hast thou said" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - The Norman Baron. "In his chamber, weak and dying" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - The Old Clock on the Stairs. "Somewhat back from the village street" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - Paul Rever's Ride. "Listen, my children, and you shall hear" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - Pegasus in Pound. "Once into a quiet village" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - A Psalm of Life. "Tell me not, in mournful numbers" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 5)
    - A Psalm of Life. "Tell me not, in mournful numbers," cont. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 6)
    - Resignation. "There is no flock, however watch'd and tended" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 6)
    - Saga of King Olaf. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 6)
    - The sea hath its pearls. "The sea hath its pearls" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 6)
    - The Skeleton in Armor. "'Speak! speak! thou fearful guest!'" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 7)
    - The Slave in the Dismal Swamp. "In dark fens of the Dismal Swamp" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 7)
    - The Slave Singing at Midnight. "Lous he sang the psalm of David!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 7)
    - The Slave's Dream. "Beside the ungathered rice he lay" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 7)
    - The Song of Hiawatha. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 7)
    - The Song of Hiawatha. cont. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - The Song of the Silent Land. "Into the silent land!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - Songo River. "Nowhere such a devious stream" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - Stars of the Summer Night! "Stars of the summer night!" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - There Was a Little Girl. "There was a little girl" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - To the River Rhone. "Thou Royal River, born of sun and shower" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - The Village Blacksmith. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 8)
    - The Village Blacksmith. "Under the spreading chestnut tree" cont. (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 9)
    - The Wave. "'Wither, thou turbid wave?'" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 9)
    - The Wreck of the Hesperus. "It was the schooner Hesperus" (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 9)
    - General (Box 4, Item 52, Envelope 9)
  - Lord Lovel. "Lord Lovel he stood at his castlegate,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 1)
  - Love Will Find Out the Way. "Over the mountains", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 2)
  - Lovelace, Richard, 1618-1658., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 3)
    - To Althea, From Prison. "When love with unconfined wings" (Box 5, Item 3)
    - To Lucasta- Going to the Wars. "Tell me not, Sweet, I am unkind" (Box 5, Item 3)
  - Loveman, Robert, 1864-1923., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 4)
    - April Rain. "It is not raining rain for me" (Box 5, Item 4)
  - Lover, Samuel, 1797-1868., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 5)
    - The Angel's Whisper. "A baby was sleeping;" (Box 5, Item 5)
    - The Low-Backed Car. "When first I saw sweet Peggy" (Box 5, Item 5)
    - Molly Bawn. "Oh, Molly Bawn, why leave me pining" (Box 5, Item 5)
    - Widow Machree. "Widow Machree, it's no wonder you frown,--" (Box 5, Item 5)
  - Lowell, James Russell, 1819-1891., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 6)
    - The Debate in the Sennit. "Here we stan' on the Constitution, by thunder!" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - My Love. "Not as all other women are" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - The Pious Editor's Creed. "I du believe in Freedom's cause" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - The Rose: A Ballad. "In his tower sat the poet" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - "Thrash away, you'll hev to rattle" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - What Mr. Robinson Thinks. "Guvener B. is a sensible man;" (Box 5, Item 6)
    - Parodies in the style of Lowell, original poems unidentified. (Box 5, Item 6)
  - Luttrell, Henry, 1765?-1851., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 7)
    - Burnham Beeches. "A Bard, dear Muse, unapt to sing" (Box 5, Item 7)
  - Lydgate, John, 1370?-1451?, 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 8)
    - London Lyckpenny. "To London once my steppes I bent" (Box 5, Item 8)
  - Lyle, Thomas., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 9)
    - Kelvin Grove. "Let us haste to Kelvin grove, bonnie lassie, O;" (Box 5, Item 9)
  - Lyly, John, 1554?-1606., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 10)
    - Cupid and Campaspe. "Cupid and Campaspe played" (Box 5, Item 10)
  - Lytle, William Haines, 1826-1863., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 11)
    - Antony and Cleopatra. "I am dying, Egypt, dying" (Box 5, Item 11)
  - Lytton, Edward George Earle Lytton Bulwer-Lytton, 1st baron, 1803-1873., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 12)
    - Melnotte's Visionary Home. "Nay, dearest, nay, if thou would'st have me paint" (Box 5, Item 12)
    - Parodies in the style of Lytton, original poems unidentified. (Box 5, Item 12)
  - Lytton, Edward Robert Bulwer-Lytton, 1st earl of, 1831-1891., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 13)
    - Parodies in the style of Lytton, original poems unidentified. (Box 5, Item 13)
  - Macaulay, Thomas Babington, 1800-1859., 3 envelopes (Box 5, Item 14)
    - The Armada. "Attend, all ye who list to hear" (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 1)
    - The Battle of the Lake Regillus. "Ho, trumpets, sound a war-note!" (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 1)
    - General (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 1)
    - General, cont. (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 2)
    - Horatius. "Lars Porsena of Clusium" (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 2)
    - Horatius. "Lars Porsena of Clusium" (cont.) (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 3)
    - Ivry. "Now glory to the Lord of Hosts" (Box 5, Item 14, Envelope 3)
  - MacDonald, George, 1824-1905., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 15)
    - Where Did You Come From? "Where did you come from, baby dear? (Box 5, Item 15)
  - MacKay, Charles, 1814-1889., 2 envelopes (Box 5, Item 16)
    - Cheer, Boys! Cheer! "Cheer, boys! cheer! no more of idle sorrow" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - Cleon and I. "Cleon hath ten thousand acres" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - An Emigrant's Blessing. "Farewell, England! blessings on thee" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - The English Girl. "Give, oh give us English welcomes" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - The Good Time Coming. "There's a good time coming, boys" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - The Inquiry. "Tell me, ye winged winds" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - John Brown, or a Plain Man's Philosophy. "I've a guinea I can spend" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - Old King Cole. "Old King Cole was a merry old soul" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 1)
    - Old King Cole. "Old King Cole was a merry old soul," cont. (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 2)
    - Tubal Cain. "Old Tubal Cain was a man of might" (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 2)
    - General. (Box 5, Item 16, Envelope 2)
  - Maginn, William, 1793-1842., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 17)
    - Parody in the style of Maginn, original poem unidentified. (Box 5, Item 17)
  - Maher, William., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 18)
    - The Night Before Larry Was Stretched. "The night before Larry was stretched" (Box 5, Item 18)
  - Mahoney, Francis Sylvester, -1866., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 19)
    - The Bells of Shandon. "With deep affection" (Box 5, Item 19)
  - Mallett, David, ca. 1705-1765., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 20)
    - William and Margaret. "'Twas at the silent, solemn hour" (Box 5, Item 20)
  - Manners, John, 1638-1711., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 21)
    - Manners and Civility. "Let Laws and Commerce, Arts and Science die" (Box 5, Item 21)
  - Mannington, George., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 22)
    - A Sorrowful Sonnet, "I waile in wo, I plunge in pain" (Box 5, Item 22)
  - Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 23)
    - The Man with the Hoe. "Bowed by the weight of centuries he leans" (Box 5, Item 23)
  - Marlowe, Christopher, 1564-1593., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 24)
    - The Passionate Shepherd to his Love. "Come live with me and be my love" (Box 5, Item 24)
    - General (Box 5, Item 24)
  - Marzials, Theophile, 1850-., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 25)
    - In the North Countree. (Box 5, Item 25)
    - Twickenham Ferry. "'Ahoy! and O-ho! and it's who for the ferry?'" (Box 5, Item 25)
  - Masefield, John, 1878-1967., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 26)
    - The Daffodil Fields. "Between the barren pasture and the wood" (Box 5, Item 26)
    - Sea-fever. "I must go down to the sea again, to the lonely sea and the sky" (Box 5, Item 26)
    - General. (Box 5, Item 26)
  - Masson, Thomas L., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 27)
    - The Real Heaven. "The golden streets of Paradise" (Box 5, Item 27)
    - The Victor. "Three riders raced on the broad highway;" (Box 5, Item 27)
  - Masters, Edgar Lee, 1869-1950., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 28)
    - General (Box 5, Item 28)
  - Mee, William., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 29)
    - Alice Gray. "She's all my fancy painted her" (Box 5, Item 29)
  - Meredith, George, 1829-1909., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 30)
    - Breath of the Briar. "O Briar-scents, on your wet wing" (Box 5, Item 30)
    - Dirge in Woods. "A wind sways the pines" (Box 5, Item 30)
    - General (Box 5, Item 30)
  - Merivale, Herman Charles, 1839-1906., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 31)
    - Venetian Boat-song. "The boatmen are calling" (Box 5, Item 31)
  - The Mermaid. "Oh, 'twas in the broad Atlantic,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 32)
  - Merrick, James, 1720-1769., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 33)
    - The Chameleon. "Oft has it been ny lot to mark" (Box 5, Item 33)
  - Merrily Danced the Quaker Bright. "Merrily danced the Quaker bright,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 34)
    - Merry, Robert, 1755-1798. See Cruscans, Della. (Box 5, Item 34)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 35)
    - General (Box 5, Item 35)
  - Miller, Joaquin, 1841-1913., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 36)
    - General (Box 5, Item 36)
  - The Miller of Dee. "There was a jolly miller once,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 37)
  - Milliken, Richard Alfred, 1767-1815., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 38)
    - The Groves of Blarney. "The groves of Blarney they look so charming" (Box 5, Item 38)
  - Milne, Alan Alexander, 1882-1956., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 39)
    - The King's Breakfast. "The King asked" (Box 5, Item 39)
    - General (Box 5, Item 39)
  - Milnes, Richard Monckton., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 40)
    - Song. "I wander'd by the brook-side" (Box 5, Item 40)
    - Strangers yet. "Strangers yet!" (Box 5, Item 40)
  - Milton, John, 1608-1674., 2 envelopes (Box 5, Item 41)
    - L'Allergo. "Hence, loathed Melancholy," (and) Il Penseroso. "Hence, vain deluding joys" (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 1)
    - An Epitaph on the Admirable Dramatic Poet, W. Shakespeare. "What needs my Shakespeare for his honour'd bones" (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 1)
    - On His Blindness. "When I consider how my light is spent" (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 1)
    - Paradise Lost. (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 1)
    - Paradise Lost, cont. (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 2)
    - Sonnet. "A book was writ of late called Tetrachordon;" (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 2)
    - To a Virtuous Young Lady. "Lady, that in the prime of earliest youth" (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 2)
    - General (Box 5, Item 41, Envelope 2)
  - The Monks of Old. "Many have told of the monks of old,", 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 42)
  - Monro, Harold, 1879-1932., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 43)
    - Solitude. "When you have tidied all things for the night" (Box 5, Item 43)
  - Montenegro, Carlota., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 44)
    - Where Are You Going, My Pretty Maid? "'Where are you going, oh my pretty maid?;" (Box 5, Item 44)
  - Moore, Clement Clark, 1779-1863., 1 envelope (Box 5, Item 45)
    - The Night Before Christmas. "'Twas the night before Christmas, when all through the house" (Box 5, Item 45)
  - Moore, Thomas, 1779-1852., 10 envelopes (Box 5, Item 46)
    - After the Battle. "Night clos'd around the conqueror's way" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - All That's Bright Must Fade. "All that's bright must fade" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - And Doth Not a Meeting Like This. "And doth not a meeting like this make amends" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - As a Beam O'er the Face of the Waters May Glow. "As a beam o'er the face of the waters may glow" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - Believe Me, If All Those Endearing Young Charms. "Believe me, if all those endearing young charms" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - A Canadian Boat Song. "Faintly as tolls the evening chime" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - Come O'er the Sea. "Come o'er the sea" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - Come Rest in this Bosom. "Come, rest in this bosom, my own stricken deer" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 1)
    - Come, Send Round the Wind. "Come, send round the wine, and leave points of belief" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - Elysium on Earth. "Come hither, come hither! by night and by day" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - Eveleen's Bower. "Oh! weep for the hour" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - Farewell! -- But Whenever You Welcome. "Farewell! - but whenever you welcome the hour" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - Fill the Bumper Fair. "Fill the bumper fair!" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - Fly Not Yet. "Fly not yet, 'tis just the hour" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - The Harp That Once through Tara's Hall. "The harp that once through Tara's halls" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 2)
    - "Here's the bower she loved so much" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - "How dear to me the hour when daylight dies" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - I Saw from the Beach. "I saw from the beach, when the morning was shining" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - The Legacy. "When in death I shall calmly recline" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - Lesbia Hath a Beaming Eye. "Lesbia hath a beaming eye" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - Let Erin Remember the Days of Old. "Let Erin remember the days of old" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - Love's Young Dream. "Oh! the days are gone, when beauty bright" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - Mary, I Believed Thee True. "Mary, I believed thee true" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - The Meeting of the Waters. "There is not in the wide world a valley so sweet" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 3)
    - The Meeting of the Waters. "There is not in the wide world a valley so sweet" (Cont.) (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 4)
    - The Minstrel Boy. "The Minstrel Boy to the war is gone" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 4)
    - The Minstrel Boy. "The Minstrel Boy to the war is gone," (Cont.) (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)
    - My Heart and Lute. "I give thee all--I can no more -" (Box 5, Item 46, Envelopes 5)